<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="13"><page Index="1"/><page Index="2"><![CDATA[CHAPTER I

               DESCRIBING PLACES AND PROFESSION



                 I.  INPUT

               Pre-Activity 1

               Please listen to the conversation between a room attendant and a guest in the hotel! Choose
               which picture is mentioned in their conversation!


















































            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Pre-Activity 2

               Please read the following conversation and discuss with your pair what is the conversation
               about!


                                              ….                     ….















                                          Mr. Smith                                                         Room Boy

               Mr. Smith    : Excuse me, do you know the nearest tourism destination here?
               Room Boy     : Yes, I know sir. There are many tourism destinations near our hotel but
                              the nearest one is Lovina beach.
               Mr. Smith    : What is something interesting about the beach?
               Room Boy     : It is not different from other beaches. It is black sand beach that offers
                              you beautiful sunset panorama. It has many beautiful coral reefs that you can
                              enjoy while diving. Lovina is best-known for its dolphin attraction. You can enjoy
                              the attraction in the early morning by booking a boat of the local people here.
                              Don’t forget to bring your camera or smartphone to capture the moment.
               Mr. Smith    : Well, it sounds interesting. Thanks a lot
               Room Boy     : My pleasure sir.

               Pre-Activity 3

               Please write three sentences for the pictures below!


                                                                   1.  ……………………………………

                                                                   2.  ……………………………………
                                                                   3.  ……………………………………























            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            2]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[1.  ……………………………………
                                                                   2.  ……………………………………

                                                                   3.  ……………………………………












                                                                   1.  ……………………………………

                                                                   2.  ……………………………………
                                                                   3.  ……………………………………













                 II. CONTENT FOCUS
                       Descriptive text is a text purposed to show or reveal a description about what people,
               things, or places look like. A particular thing, person, or place is described from the view of
               five senses. It commonly gives readers clear description about the person, thing, or place by
               presenting their physical forms or characteristics (sight), fragrances (smell), textures (touch),
               tastes or flavors (tastes), and sounds (hear).

                   a. Describing Place

                   Describing  place  is  a  descriptive  text  which  provides  readers  a  deep  description  of  a
               particular place by reviewing the characteristics which make it different from other places.
               Let’s see the text below!

                                 Busungbiu Rice Terrace                                    Title
                        Busungbiu  Rice  Terrace  is  the  tourism
                 destination  located  in  Kekeran  village,  Busungbiu,
                 Buleleng, Bali. It is about 30 kilometers from Singaraja
                 city offering a stunning panoramic view of rice terraces
                 surrounded by green hills. There are visible strands of a
                 sparkling river with flowing water in the middle of rice                  Identification
                 fields. It does not only spoil the visitors’ sight with the
                 rice terraces but it also shows the natural panorama of
                 mountains  and  rainforests.  The  fresh  air  and  calm
                 surrounding  atmosphere  with  sweet  singing  birds
                 complete the beauty of Busungbiu Rice Terrace.




            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            3]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[There are several activities that visitors can enjoy.
                The visitors can have a very comfortable and relax picnic
                in  the  provided  gazebos.  It  is  recommended  to  try  the
                trekking  activities  for  enjoying  the  beautiful  rice  fields.
                Joining farmers’ activities are the most attractive ones in
                Busungbiu Rice Terrace. The visitors are invited to plant                  Description
                the rice and introduced to Subak Irrigation System. It is a
                traditional irrigation system of Balinese farmers. All of the
                activities  offered  in  this  destination  are  suitable  for  the
                visitors who love nature. It refreshes them from the city
                crowd.

                   b. Describing Profession

                   Describing  profession  is  a  descriptive  text  purposed  to  show  readers  a  specific
               description of particular profession or person with his or her job. It shows the characteristics
               that differentiate that profession from others. Let’s read the descriptive text bellow!

                                      Laundry Valet                                                      Title

                            Laundry  valet  is  a  hotel  staff  works  under
                housekeeping department. Laundry valet position is a part
                of laundry section. People who work as a laundry valet is
                responsible for  ensuring  all  the laundry  services  for  the            Identification
                hotel’s  guest.  They  collect  the  laundry  from  the  guest
                rooms and delivery it back when it is ready. Laundry valet
                is  shifted  for  as  a  morning  staff  and  evening  staff  to
                handle the laundry along the guest stay at the hotel.

                            Picking up and turning back guests’ laundry is not
                the only task for laundry valets. Checking the condition of
                guests’  laundry  to  consider  the technique and  chemical
                used  for  washing  is  laundry  valets’  task.  They  need  to
                ensure  that  there  is  no  damage  on  the  guests’  laundry
                before the washing process. Sorting and folding the clean                  Description
                laundry are other tasks for the laundry valets before the
                clean laundry is ready to return.  The last task is reporting
                technical problems occur during the washing process to
                maintenance team. Those all the tasks of laundry valets in
                the hotel.




                   c. The Characteristics of Descriptive Text
                   There are several characteristics of descriptive text which make it different from other
               kind of texts, such as;

                   1.  Generic Structure
                       -  Identification:  general  introduction  about  the  place,  thing,  or  person  that  will  be
                         described in  the text.  It  begins  with  the  general  definition  or  appearance of the
                         described object.







            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[-  Description: specific description about the place, thing, or person that is mention in
                         identification part. It consists of clear description about the forms, features, colors,
                         and anything related to the object.
                   2.  The Use of Adjective and Action Verb
                       -  Adjective  is  used  for  clarifying  and  modifying  the  noun,  for  example;  beautiful
                         scenery, enjoyable spot, hard worker, etc.
                       -  Action verb for showing an activity done by the participant or object described in
                         the text, for example;
                         a.  The room attendant works in housekeeping department
                         b. Lovina beach offers a beautiful sunset view to the tourist
                   3.  The Use of Simple Present Tense
                           The sentence pattern used is in the form of simple present since it tells the fact or
                      general truth about the object, for example;
                       a.  Standard room is the low-budged hotel room
                       b.  They are domestic visitors
                       c.  Room attendant cleans the guest room
                       d.  Deluxe room has many facilities

                  III. LANGUAGE FOCUS

                   a. Grammar

                                             Simple Present Tense Formula
                   1.  Nominal Sentence

                           Nominal  sentence  is  a  sentence  used  for  showing  the  characteristics  of  a
                    described object without indicating an action. Let’s see the formula in the following table!

                                         Subject        To be          Adjective/Noun
                                            I            Am      - Beautiful/ Field
                                           You                   - Clean/ Room
                                          They           Are     - Calm/ Sheet
                                           We                    -  Dry/ Room attendant
                                           She            Is     - Fresh/ Laundry valet
                                           He                    - Panoramic/ Scenery
                                            It                   - Relax/ Atmosphere
                                     Person’s name               - Sweet/ Towel


                               Positive       Subject + To be + Adjective/Noun
                               Sentence       They are linen runners It is a cultural destination
                               Negative       Subject + To be + not + Adjective/ Noun
                               Sentence       You are not in housekeeping department Aluna Hotel is
                                              not five stars hotel
                               Interrogative  To be + Subject + Adjective/Noun
                               Sentence       Are you a room boy? Is it a deluxe room?








            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            5]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Example

                  Please  read  the  following  dialogues!  The  italic  sentence  is  the  example  of  nominal
                  sentence.


                          Candra : What do you think about Garuda Wisnu Kencana? Is it
                                    interesting?

                          Maha  : It is an interesting destination. I love that place

                          Candra : I love it too. Let’s visit Garuda Wisnu Kencana again

                          Maha  : Alright



                            Frank  : Hai John, congratulation! You’ve got a new job!

                           John  : Thanks a lot, I am a room attendant now!
                           Frank  : Yeahh, how about Rosie? Is she a room attendant too?

                           John  : She is not a room attendant but an order taker in the same

                                    department as mine



                   2.  There are/ There is
                           The formula of “there are” and “there is” depends on the quantity of noun or object
                   referred in the text.

                               Positive      There is            Singular noun or object
                               sentence      There are           Plural nouns or objects
                               Negative      There is + not      Singular noun or object
                               sentence      There are + not     Plural nouns or objects
                               Interrogative  Is there           Singular noun or object
                               sentence      Are there           Singular noun or object


                   Example

                   Please read the following dialogue to find out the examples!

                   Mr. Nyoman  : Good morning sir, I am Nyoman, the room attendant who will clean your
                                   room.

                   Mr. Jean     : Good morning, you can clean my room and I’ll go out for a while. I need to
                                              get some fresh air. What are the recreation facilities that I can enjoy in this
                                  hotel?

                   Mr. Nyoman  : There are three recreation facilities in our hotel sir. They are spa and
                                  message, swimming pool, and fitness center. If you want something new,
                                  there is one destination you have to visit sir. It is our new water spot outside
                                  the hotel.





            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            6]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Mr. Jean    : What a good information. Thank you

                   Mr. Nyoman: You’re welcome




                   3.  Verbal Sentence

                           Verbal sentence is a sentence used for describing the activity or habit done by the
                   described object. This sentence is indicated by the use of “verb”.

                     Subject            Verb 1                Object                  Adverb
                     I                  Clean                 Room                    Slowly
                     You                Sweep                 Floor                   Repeatedly
                     They               Mop                   Lobby                   Hardly
                     We                 Squeeze               Window                  Carefully
                     Subject            Verb 1 + s/es         Object                  Adverb
                     She                Cleans                Pantry                  Quickly
                     He                 Folds                 Towel                   Neatly
                     It                 Washes                Linen                   Daily
                     Person’s name      Strips                Bed                     Epically


                     Positive Sentence       Subject + Verb 1 (s/es) + Object + Adverb
                                             She folds many towels neatly
                                             They squeeze the windows carefully
                     Negative Sentence       Subject + Do/Does + Not + Object + Adverb
                                             She does not fold many towels neatly
                                             They do not squeeze the windows carefully
                     Interrogative           Do/Does + Subject + V1 + Object + Adverb
                     Sentence                Does she fold many towels neatly?
                                             Do they squeeze the windows carefully?




                    Example
                    Please read the following dialogue to find out the examples!

                    Rony: Hello Anne, how are you?
                    Anne: I’m not feeling well, how about you?
                    Rony: I’m a bit tired. The high season gives us an extra work, right?
                    Anne: Perfectly correct, I clean 30 rooms everyday. It is over than the usual job.
                    Rony: Yeah, I know it. The supervisor said that the room attendant handles 25- 30 rooms a
                    day.
                    Anne: We do not have enough time to break. How about you? Do you face the same thing?
                    Rony: Yes, I do. I serve many guests for the breakfast. I think I am gonna die soon. Does
                    Aldi tell you about the upcoming event in our hotel?
                    Anne: Yes, he does. It will be a great event for celebrating lunar year. We are going to be
                    busier than today
                    Rony: Absolutely yes.







            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            7]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Additional explanation about simple present and adverbs

                                      Additional Video 1


                                      Additional Video 2



                   4.  The Formula of “Has/Have”
                           In  simple  present  tense,  “Has”  and  “Have”  are  categorized  as  a  verb  with  a
                   different form with the same meaning. Both of those verbs are used based on the subject.
                   It can be seen in the following box.

                   Subject                                              Object (Singular/Plural)
                   I                                                    Towel/Towels
                   You                             Have                 Bathmat/Bathmats
                   They                                                 Pillow/Pillows
                   We                                                   Slipper/Slippers
                   Subject                                              Object
                   She                                                  Shower cap/ Shower caps
                   He                               Has                 Comb/ Combs
                   It                                                   Saver kit/ Saver kits
                   Person’s name                                        Amenity/Amenities

                   Positive            Subject + Has/Have + Object
                   Sentence
                                       She has some towels
                                       We have several souvenirs
                   Negative            Subject + Don’t/Doesn’t + Have + Object
                   Sentence
                                       The hotel doesn’t have good facilities
                                       They don’t have a luxurious room
                   Interrogative       Do/Does + Subject + Have + Object
                                       Do you have any comb?
                                       Does she have any saver kit?

                  Example

                  Please read the following dialogue to find out the examples!

                  Denise  : Do you have any recommended hotel for our business trip?

                  Rosaline : How about Dynasty Hotel? It has great facilities
                  Denise  : Does it have a private balcony? I need a private space for working

                  Rosaline : Yes, it does but the hotel doesn’t have smoking areas.

                  Denise  : It sounds good because I don’t like to smoke. We don’t have enough time. Let’s
                  book the room first.

                  Rosaline : Yes, I’m going to contact the receptionist soon.






            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            8]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[b.  Vocabularies

                  How to pronounce;



                       -   Clean /kliːn/           - Dust /dʌst/         - Bleach /bliːtʃ/
                       -   Chemical /ˈkemɪkl/      - Finish /ˈfɪnɪʃ/     - Broom /bruːm/

                       -   Comb /kəʊm/             - Fold /fəʊld/        - Damp /dæmp/
                       -   Dirty /ˈdɜːti/          - Filthy /ˈfɪlθi/     -Deodorizer /diˈoʊdəraɪzə/
                       -   Disturb /dɪˈstɜːb/      - Freshen /ˈfreʃn/    - Glove /ɡlʌv/

                       -   Drain /dreɪn/           - Hang /hæŋ/          - Polish /ˈpɒlɪʃ/
                       -   Entry /ˈentri/          - Iron /ˈaɪən/        - Rinse /rɪns/
                       -   Equipment /ɪˈkwɪpmənt/  - Messy /ˈmesi/       -Sanitize /ˈsænɪtaɪz/

                       -   Mop /mɒp/               - Neat /niːt/         - Stain /steɪn/
                       -   Move /muːv/             - Slipper /ˈslɪpər/   - Squeeze /skwiːz/



                   c.  Terms

                   The definition for;

                   Amenity: a free item or service offered by the  High season: a season where the hotel is
                    hotel to the guest placed in their rooms.      fully booked
                   Carry caddy: a place for the chemicals and tools  Low  season:  a  season  where the hotel  is
                    used for cleaning the room.                    rarely booked
                   Dry  cleaning:  a  cleaning  process  in  laundry  Lounge:  a public  area in  the  hotel  for  the
                    without  using  water  but  it  uses  a  solvent  guest to relax
                    chemical
                   Deluxe room: a kind of hotel room which has  Recreation:  hotel  facilities  specifically  for
                    medium facilities and prices                   entertainment or amusement
                   Duster: a tool used for dusting the materials or  Vacant: a condition of room hotel with no
                   furniture                                       guest


                   IV. TASK
                   Task 1.

                   Please complete the text below by writing a related passage to the provided paragraph
                   and decide what the title is!



                                                        Title


                           ………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………

                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………
                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………

                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………




            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………

                   …………………………………………………………………………………

                           An order taker has several job desks which are different from other housekeeping

                   staffs. Taking the guests’ request or order is the first task of order taker. The second task
                   is  informing  and  reporting  the  guests’  order  to  room  attendants.  After  informing  and
                   reporting the guests’ order, the order taker has a responsibility to ask confirmation to the

                   guests whether their orders have been delivered or not. The last, the order taker fills the

                   reporting form for noting the accepted orders that have been processed. Sometimes, the
                   order taker also has a task for confirming and accepting the requests from front office
                   department about the booked room. Those are the different tasks that are done by the

                   order taker in housekeeping department.




                                                         Title




                           The Mount Batur Hike is located in Kintamani, Bali. It is one of the most popular
                   destinations. It offers an enjoyable sunrise trekking experience for the visitors. It is an

                   effortless destination that can be visited from any part of Bali Island. It only takes 45 – 1
                   hour from the central city of each regency. The visitors can catch an amazing view of the

                   sunrise from the top of mountain. Many guides assist the visitors for the hiking track.

                           ………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………

                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………
                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………

                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………
                   ……………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………………
                   …………………………………………………………………………………




















            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            10]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Task 2.


                  Please  complete  the  following  transactional  conversation  by  working  with  your  pair.
                  Complete the dialogue based on the expression of describing place or job related to the
                  topic give.  Use a role-play approach and reenact the conversation with your friend in front
                  of the classroom!
                  Room Facilities


                  A    : Excuse me, are you a room boy? Can you escort me to the room number 405? I have
                            been late and leave by my parents.

                  B   : Yes, I can mam, I’ll escort you to your room.
                  A   : …………………………………………………………………..

                  B   : …………………………………………………………………..
                  A   : …………………………………………………………………..
                  B   : ……………………………………………………………………



                  Tourism Destination


                  A   : I feel boring to stay at the hotel all day long.

                  B   : Sorry sir, can I recommend you a destination to visit?
                  A   : …………………………………………………………..

                  B   : ……………………………………………………………
                  A   : ……………………………………………………………

                  B   : …………………………………………………………….



                  My New Job


                  A   : Mom, I have good news. I have been hired as linen runner at The Sillas Hotel
                  B   : What job is that darling?

                  A   : …………………………………………………………….
                  B   : …………………………………………………………….

                  A   : …………………………………………………………….
                  B   : …………………………………………………………….


                  Task 3.

                       Please create your own website by writing a descriptive text about tourism destination,
                  hotel, or profession. Choose only one topic or object to describe and share the link of your
                  website to your teacher and friends!





            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            11]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[V.  REFLECTION

                       Let’s do a reflection about yourself and the material that you have been studied in this
                    unit!
                     At the end of this unit, I understand
                     about:                               1………………………………………………….
                                                          2………………………………………………….

                                                          3………………………………………………….
                                                          4………………………………………………….

                                                          Etc ……………………..
                     At the end of this unit, I am able to:   1………………………………………………….

                                                          2………………………………………………….
                                                          3………………………………………………….

                                                          4………………………………………………….
                                                          Etc ………………………………………………..

                     There are several problems and the  1………………………………………………….
                     concept  that  I  don’t  understand  in
                     this unit, such as:                  2………………………………………………….
                                                          3………………………………………………….
                                                          4………………………………………………….

                                                          Etc ………………………………………………..








            ENGLISH FOR HOUSE KEEPING – XII                                                            12]]></page></pages></Search>
